srilankan.lk 2015-12-06

# Privacy Policy

## INTRODUCTION

SriLankan Airlines Limited (“SriLankan”) collects Customer Data to provide you with its services.  SriLankan takes its responsibility to protect Customer Data seriously and has always respected and protected the privacy of its Customers.

This Policy (“Privacy Policy”) outlines the types of personal and other information that SriLankan collects about its Customers and describes how SriLankan obtains, stores, uses, and shares such Data. This Privacy Policy applies to information that you provide or that we collect when you use our websites, mobile services, Global Contact Centre, or any other services offered by SriLankan or provided by third parties in connection with our services.

## DATA WE COLLECT

SriLankan will ask you to provide personal information when you use our services.  We may collect your information in a variety of ways, including through our websites, mobile services, and Global Contact Centre.  We also may collect such information through third parties that help us provide services to our customers, such as travel agents with whom we have contractual arrangements.  
We respect your choice not to share personal information with us.  However, if you decide to use our services without providing such information when it is required, your experience  in using our website could be degraded. 

The personal information that we collect about you (“Customer Data”) may include, for example:

  * Identification information, including your name, gender, date of birth, and details from your passport or other identification documents
  * Contact details, such as your e-mail address, telephone, mobile number, postal address, and fax number
  * Credit and debit card information, including your card number, expiry date, cardholder’s name, billing address, and other billing information
  * Location details, travelling details, flight numbers, itinerary, seat and meal preferences, any reservations made for value-added services, and information about your travel companions
  * Information relating to your membership in our Frequent Flyer Programme. 

When you use our online or mobile services, we also may collect information (such as “cookie” data) that does not identify you personally.  Our collection, use, and sharing of such information is discussed below (see the “Cookies” section).

## USE OF CUSTOMER DATA

We use your Customer Data to provide the services that you request and to enhance your customer experience.  For example, we use your information: 

  * To process and administer flight reservations and any other requests that you make in connection with our services
  * To process and administer reservations for our cargo services
  * To process payments
  * To enrol and administer the membership of our Frequent Flyer Programme
  * To provide you with information about promotions, products, and services offered by SriLankan, or by our business partners.
  * To respond to your queries about our services 
  * To investigate any claims or complaints you make relating to our services
  * To improve the security and safety of our services
  * To comply with legal or regulatory requirements, respond to requests by law enforcement authorities, or respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process
  * To defend our interests or to establish, protect, or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims
  * To offer you services in your local language and currency for your convenience

## DISCLOSURE OF CUSTOMER DATA

SriLankan does not sell, rent, or trade Customer Data to third parties.  However, we may share your information with certain parties as follows:

  * With all entities in the SriLankan Airlines’ Group, including but not limited to SriLankan and SriLankan Catering Limited
  * With third party service providers, contractors, and agents providing services such as hotels, insurance packages, duty free items on board, call centres, data processing and analytics, marketing and research, limousine services, distribution, revenue optimization, payment, and other services to SriLankan in connection with the operations of the business of SriLankan Airlines’ Group,
  * With other business partners of SriLankan such as code-share partners, sea and land transport service providers, and members of any airline alliance in which SriLankan is a member
  * With the frequent flyer programmes of operators of other partner airlines
  * With Internet payment gateway service providers, banks, credit/debit card companies, and other financial services providers
  * With partners of the Frequent Flyer Programme of SriLankan
  * With any law enforcement authority or governmental institution for security, customs, immigration, or any other investigative purpose. SriLankan shall not be bound to verify the legitimacy and lawfulness of such request by a law enforcement authority or any governmental institution and SriLankan shall be entitled to disclose Customer Data in order to duly comply with such request. 
  * To comply with legal or regulatory requirements, respond to requests by law enforcement authorities, or respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process
  * To defend our interests or to establish, protect, or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims
  * When we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to our property or the physical safety of any person, or violations of our terms and conditions
  * To facilitate the financing, securitization, insuring, sale, assignment, or other disposal of all or part of our business or assets.

## INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFER AND DATA PROTECTION LAWS

SriLankan is an international commercial airline operating in many different jurisdictions and, accordingly, Customer Data collected in one jurisdiction might be stored, transferred, or accessed worldwide in different jurisdictions. The protections for Customer Data differ from one jurisdiction to another and thus when transferred, your Customer Data may be subject to different or lesser protections than in your country of residence.  By providing your Customer Data, you acknowledge and agree to the transfer of such Data to jurisdictions that may have lesser protections for Customer Data. 

## CONSENT AND UPDATES

By providing information to SriLankan or one of our service providers, you  acknowledge the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and you consent to be bound by this Policy.

You should ensure that the information we hold about you is current and accurate at all times.  .  If you have a dedicated account with SriLankan, you may login to that account and update your information as necessary.  You also may have a right under applicable data protection law to access, amend, and/or request deletion of other information that we collect about you. To do so, please contact us at [Customer@srilankan.com](mailto:Customer@srilankan.com).  In some cases, we may charge a nominal fee for processing such a request.  Although SriLankan shall not be responsible for the accuracy of the Customer Data, it shall have the right to verify the details in any request made to update Customer Data.

SriLankan reserves the right to refuse to disclose the information that we hold if any law enforcement authority instructs us not to disclose information or, in the reasonable opinion of SriLankan, such disclosure could otherwise be harmful to SriLankan or any third party.  For example, requests made in connection with fraudulent activities or in contravention of law will be refused. 

You may withdraw your consent to receive promotional emails either by unsubscribing through the link provided in such an email or by changing the settings in your personal account with us. 

## COOKIES

SriLankan may use cookies to enhance your experience in searching our services.  Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that are sent to your computer when you visit websites and online services.  If your web browser’s preferences are set to accept it, the cookie is stored on your computer’s hard drive.  Cookies enable our and other websites to recognize your preferences and to tailor content to you.      

Like many websites, SriLankan,com does not currently respond to “do not track” browser headers.  But you can take steps to limit tracking by erasing cookies from your computer’s hard drive and by setting your browser to block all cookies or warn you before a cookie is stored.  We respect your choice to accept or reject any cookies.  However, your rejection of cookies may prevent you from using some of the features on our website or mobile services.

## SECURITY

In order to safeguard Customer Data, SriLankan has in place commercially reasonable technical and procedural mechanisms.  However, no level of security can entirely eliminate the risk of unauthorized access or use of data collected and stored online.  Moreover, you should take care not to disclose your information online, including in any social media, and you should take reasonable steps to preserve the confidentiality of your Customer Data.

The third party websites linked to on SriLankan’s website are operated by third parties.  SriLankan does not endorse any of these websites and shall not be responsible for the information, content, accuracy, or opinions expressed in such third party websites.  Moreover, when you access and use any third party website, the information that you disclose is subject to the privacy policies of those websites, and not this Privacy Policy.

## REVISIONS 

SriLankan will amend this Privacy Policy from time to time in accordance with applicable laws and regulations, and the updated version will be posted on this website.  We request that you revisit this website from time to time for updates on the Privacy Policy.  The Privacy Policy may be translated into different languages, and in the event of any inconsistency among the versions, the English version shall prevail.

## CONTACT US

If you have any comments or queries about this Privacy Policy, please contact SriLankan in writing at the address stated below or contact us at [Customer@srilankan.com](mailto:Customer@srilankan.com):

SriLankan Airlines Limited  
Customer Affairs Department  
Airline Centre  
Bandaranaike International Airport  
Katunayake  
Sri Lanka.
